Hello.
In this next section, we're going to create a bunch of blueprint systems.
The first blueprint system we're going to create is an Apple pickup.
So we're going to make it so our player character can pick up and collect more apples in the game to
get started.
I want us to create a new folder and call it items.
Ben, if we head inside here, if we just right click and Go Blueprint class, select an actor and call
this Apple pickup.
If we open it up.
Under component.
Go ad and look for papers.
Right.
Will the Sprite select the apple that we imported a while ago and scroll down and under Collision Presets
set it to has no collision.
If we scroll back up.
Under scale, I'm going to see my apple up.
So it's three in the x, Y and Z.
Then do we go ad and look for staycation?
Make it fit around your apple.
Once you've done that with this sphere selected, if we scroll down and go to on component, we can
overlap and on component we can overlap.
If we just drag off our actor and look for cost to play a beep or whatever your character is called,
whenever our player character overlaps this, we're going to cost to them.
And this cost will allow us to reference any variable or customer event inside of our player character.
Just right click on this and promote it to a variable.
So the first thing we're going to do if our player actor overlaps this Apple box is check to see if
they have the maximum amount of apples.
If they don't, then we're going to give them some apples.
If they do, then we're going to give them no apples.
So if we just drag off our player reference and get the amount of apples that they have.
We're going to check to see if this is equal to the maximum amount of apples that they have.
So if we just drag a here and look, we'll get max apples.
And if this is true.
So I'll drive up here and look for brunch.
That means my poor character has all the apples that they can hold.
So we're going to do nothing.
However, if this is false, that means my character can hold and store some more apples.
If that's the case, we're going to give them some more apples.
So to do that, we can drag in our player, BP, and drag up here and get apples.
And if we just try and look for ADD.
And I'm going to give my character five apples every time they collect an apple.
You can make this whatever value you want.
And then we can just drag up here and look for set apples.
And connect us into here and connect us and you folks, after our player character collects the apple,
we're going to destroy this actor.
So if I just drag up here and destroy.
So.
There's one more thing we need to do, though.
Let's say my character has 29 apples.
If they go over and now pick up an apple, they're now going to have 34 apples.
In order to prevent this, because I made my player character have a maximum amount of apples of 30.
What we can do is add a clamp.
So if I just drag up here and look for cramp integer and pick up the return value into here.
Under the minimum value.
Just put one.
And under the maximum value, we can drag off the player BP, and get the maximum amount of apples.
This comp will ensure that this value can only be as high as the value inside of here.
So we put the value as 30.
So even if my player character has a 29 apples and they pick up an apple which gives them five, they'll
still only be given 30 apples because we set up a clamp which limits the amount of maximum apple that
they can hold.
So we can compile and test this all out.
If I close this and I'm going to drag it in my apple pick up.
I'll put it on the -20.
I think that's why I put everything.
And if I could play.
So I have five apples.
If I collect this.
I have ten apples, but it's not updated on my UI.
So there's one more thing I need to do if I go back to my apple pickup.
After we tell the game that we have some more apples before we destroy our actor, we can then drag
in our as player BP reference.
And if you remember in our player character, we made this variable called HUD reference.
In my Apple pickup, we can drag up it and look for HUD reference and get HUD reference, and then we
can call the update apples.
And this will just update the mouth apples on my HUD.
So show the correct values.
And now if I just connect all these nodes.
And go compile and save.
Now, if I go play and I collect this apple, I should now have ten apples and my HUD will also update.
If I gave my character, let's say, dirty apples and start off with.
And I go play.
If I try and overlap this, this apple will still remain because I still have some apples.
If, say I throw away one of my apples, I now have 29 and I cannot pick up this apple.
Nice with this.
We have made an apple pickup.